Robert Ross Peterson

http://robertpeterson.io contact@robertpeterson.io

SUMMARY

I earned my stripes at IBM, experienced startup life by founding Parseix, excelled in management at the Texas health department, transformed winter retreats programs at the Lama Foundation, and today I have a passion for helping organizations thrive that value interconnectedness, sustainability and altruism.

EDUCATION

MS Meditation, Institute for Applied Meditation MS Computer Engineering, University of Florida

Tucson, AZ Gainesville, FL

EXPERIENCE

IT MANAGEMENT CONSULTANT – RobertPeterson.io Present

Hadley, MA

- Private consulting practice
- Experience encompasses academic, non-profit, and government sectors

WINTER PROGRAMS GUARDIAN – Lama Foundation 2015 - 2016

Questa, NM

- The Lama Foundation is the oldest inter-faith community of its kind in North America. Many celebrated spiritual teachers such as Mirabai Starr, Ram Dass, Pema Chödrön, Jack Kornfield, and Thomas Keating began by teaching at Lama
- As a Lama Resident, oversaw winter retreat programs, invited and communicated with lineage representatives / teachers and staffed retreat liaisons
- Increasing the caliber of winter programs resulting in two more retreats than the previous year and a 200% increase in budget via additional funding and donations
- Program encompassed seven retreats including 10-day mindfulness contemplative retreat, Heart-Rhythm Meditation retreat, Native-American retreat, and NVC workshop

2012 - 2015

HEALTHCARE IT MANAGER — Texas Health & Human Services (HHSC) Austin, TX



- Managed backend systems for Medicaid, SNAP Food Benefits, Prenatal Healthcare, and Affordable Care Act (ACA)
- Systems process benefits for 15% of Texas population or ~4.4 million
- Served as team leader for 8 staff members and various auxiliary consultants
- Through strategic hiring of talent, automation projects, and restructuring of team processes, transformed team from below average to most productive in department
- Designed security implementation for Texas/Federal ACA system using DES cryptography, LDAP, and DataPower XSLT

2012

Williamsville, NY



- CO-FOUNDER parseix.com William Designed and implemented front-end of initial offering using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, & Highcharts
- Successfully hired and created requirements documentation for visual designer

2010 - 2012

INTEGRATION ARCHITECT — IBM Tivoli

Austin, TX



- Agile project lead responsible for ten engineers for Business Service Management offering
- Contributions enabled successful launch of IBM product in 1Q 2012

2005 - 2010

IT CONSULTANT — IBM Websphere

Austin, TX



Conducted business internationally for over 50 customers, many of which are Fortune 500 companies, in industries including financial, insurance, aerospace, energy, and retail

 Developed complex client solutions with a variety of technology including jQuery/Dojo JavaScript, CSS, REST, JavaEE, SQL, XSLT, and Web Services



IT ANALYST — Boeing Integrated Defense Systems

St Louis, MO

Designed Oracle PL/SQL database application for F-16, F-18, C-17, & missile production

NOTABLE PUBLICATIONS

IBM Press

- Book: Persistence In the Enterprise, IBM Press, May 2008 (ISBN-0131587560)
- Book: WebSphere Application Server V6, IBM Redbooks, May 2005 (ISBN-0738490601)
- Bridging Web 2.0 and SOA with DataPower, WebSphere Technical Journal, September 2011



- Integrating WebSphere Service Registry with Tivoli, IBM developerWorks, December 2010
- Leverage Existing WAS J2EE Resources with Apache Geronimo, SYS-CON, May 2006
- US Patent 20090019421: Runtime Machine Supported Method Level Caching, January 2009
- US Patent 20080133538: Background File Sharing in Peer-To-Peer (P2P) File Sharing Network, June 2008

NOTABLE CONFERENCE TALKS





- Tivoli and WebSphere Integration, IBM PULSE Conference, March 2012
- DataPower in a Web 2.0 World, IBM IMPACT Conference, May 2010
- Case Studies for WebSphere Service Registry, WebSphere Services Technical Conference, April 2008
- Aspect-Oriented Programming with Eclipse for J2EE, WebSphere Technical Conference, March 2006

ADDITIONAL DISTINCTIONS

- Texas HHSC Leadership Community Member, invited to leadership meetings and training
- IBM Master Inventor, title awarded for outstanding IP contributions to IBM
- IBM General Manager Award (among numerous others OTAA, Stock Awards, Bravo Awards)